sourcefabric.org 2019-12-23

# Sourcefabric Privacy and Data Policy | Sourcefabric

POLICY CHANGES

Sourcefabric may change this Policy from time to time. Any and all changes will be reflected on this page. Substantive changes will also be announced through the standard mechanisms through which Sourcefabric communicates with the Sourcefabric community, including Sourcefabric's mailing list and newsletters.

Data retention

We will retain any information collected for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Policy unless a longer retention period is required by law and/or regulations.

More information

If you want to know exactly what information we store about you, please contact us by email at [privacy@sourcefabric.org](mailto:privacy@sourcefabric.org) (or write to Sourcefabric, z.ú., Salvátorská 10, 110 00 Prague 1, Czech Republic) and we’ll deal with your request within seven days.

Unless otherwise specified, all Sourcefabric policies (such as Terms of Service and this Privacy and Data Policy, Security policy) are shared between Sourcefabric z.ú. and Sourcefabric GmbH. This document will refer to Sourcefabric z.ú., Sourcefabric Ventures s.r.o and Sourcefabric GmbH collectively as ‘Sourcefabric’ when describing practices that apply to both. We will refer to each individually when describing practices that only apply only to one.

By using Sourcefabric websites and services offered by Sourcefabric, in particular Sourcefabric´s applications, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Policy. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions of this Policy, please do not use the website or our services.

For Sourcefabric, the protection and confidentiality of your data is of particular importance. Personal data is collected and used strictly within the legal limits of applicable data protection law. With this privacy policy, we inform about:

1\. General aspects such as the data controller and general principles of the collection and use of your personal data by Sourcefabric,

2\. Personal data we collect and use when you sign-up and log-in on our platform / application,

3\. What happens when end-users use applications with content that was published through the Sourcefabric platform, and

4\. Personal data we collect and use when you visit our website Sourcefabric.org.

**1\. General Aspects**

**1.1 Data Controller/Contact:**

The data controller for the purpose of data protection law is Sourcefabric z.ú. Salvátorská 10, 110 00 Prague 1, Czech Republic . Please feel free to address any questions or concerns regarding data privacy to [privacy@sourcefabric.org](mailto:privacy@sourcefabric.org).

**1.2. Collection and Use of your Personal Data**

Sourcefabric collects and uses your personal data strictly within the legal limits of the data protection law of the Federal Republic of Germany. We inform you below of the type, extent and purpose of any collection and use of personal data. You can access this information at any time on our website at: www.sourcefabric.org/en/home/policies/

**1.3. Sharing Data**

As a general rule, your personal data will be shared with third parties without your express prior consent only in the cases described below:

From time to time, we may require the assistance of contractually hired third parties and external service providers in order to provide our services, for instance regarding hosting or processing of payments (PayPal, credit card, etc.). In these cases, we share information with such companies or individuals to enable them to carry out their tasks. Such external service providers are carefully selected and regularly checked in order to ensure your privacy. Service providers may only use the data for the purposes specified by Sourcefabric. Service providers are furthermore contractually and / or legally obliged to process data strictly in compliance with EU GDPR and in accordance with Sourcefabric’s specifications.

If it serves investigations of illegal use of our services or is required to pursue legal claims, personal data may be shared with law enforcement agencies and third party victims. Such transfer of data will be made only where there is specific evidence for illegal or abusive conduct. Data may further be shared where it serves the enforcement of terms of use or other contractual agreements. Sourcefabric is furthermore legally obliged to disclose certain information to certain public entities upon request. Such entities include law enforcement agencies that investigate administrative offences subject to fines, and tax authorities.

**1.4. Deletion of your data**

Your data will be deleted upon being no longer required for the aforementioned purposes. If you delete your user account, your profile will be deleted as well. To the extent that Sourcefabric is legally obliged to archive, such data will be blocked and will not be available for productive use.

**1.5. Right to access and correction**

Of course you are entitled, upon request, to disclosure regarding your personal data that we are storing. You are also entitled to have any incorrect data corrected and rights to blocking or deletion. Please address any requests in such matters to [privacy@sourcefabric.org](mailto:privacy@sourcefabric.org) or write to us at the address stated above.

2\. Sign-up and Log-in

**2.1. Automatic Data Collection**

When you access one of  Sourcefabric websites, your browser automatically transmits certain data for technical reasons. The following data is stored separately from any other data you may transmit to us: Date and time of access, browser type and version, operating system, URL of the website visited prior to ours and amount of sent data. This data is stored for purely technical reasons and is never associated with any particular individual.

**2.2. Cookies**

Sourcefabric stores so-called “Cookies” to provide you with a wide range of functionalities and enhance website usage comfort. “Cookies” are tiny files stored on your computer through your browser. If you do not wish to receive “Cookies”, you may deactivate storing “Cookies” on your computer by changing your browser settings accordingly. Please note that the functioning of the website may be impaired and the range of functionalities may be limited if you deactivate “Cookies”.

**2.3. Mandatory Information**

In order to use all services offered by Sourcefabric, in particular Sourcefabric´s applications, you are required to register. This requires you to enter your name, your e-mail address, your company name and a password. This data is required to create and administer a user account for you and to enable you to fully enjoy the services of Sourcefabric after you have logged in. To give you a better service, such data may be hosted in CRM systems or similar tools, such as amocrm.com.

If you decide to use services offered by Sourcefabric that are subject to a charge, you are required to provide your payment information as well as your postal address.

**2.4. Using the Service**

Users can upload a variety of content such as texts, images, videos and music files to and via Sourcefabric´s applications. This data may occasionally, but not usually, contain data that may be qualified as personal data. Sourcefabric is not responsible for data content uploaded by the user and is neither interested in this data nor analysing this data in any way. Sourcefabric will only process and store this data within the framework of the provision of the service in the scope described in the terms and conditions of your contract in order to be able to provide the contractual service. Sourcefabric will neither use, modify or process the data beyond the aforementioned scope.

**2.5. Further information**

In addition, Sourcefabric offers you the possibility to enter further information on its website in case you decide to contact us. The information requested by Sourcefabric will then depend on your request and will be specified in the input mask. In addition, free-text fields allow you to enter more information. Sourcefabric uses the information you enter to process your request.

**2.6. Newsletter**

Sourcefabric offers a free newsletter service. In its newsletter, Sourcefabric informs you about changes to the Sourcefabric services. You may opt out of the newsletter at any time. Each newsletter contains a link to opt out of receiving any future newsletters.

3\. Content published through the Sourcefabric Applications

Sourcefabric allows its customers to integrate their uploaded content as outlined in Sec. 2.4 above into their own applications. This happens through an application programming interface (API) that delivers content stored on Sourcefabric’s servers into these applications.

The software development kits (SDK) provided by Sourcefabric are optionally embedded in such applications and solely facilitate developers to request and work with content from Sourcefabric’s servers. The APIs and SDKs are not collecting any personal data of end users (e.g. tracking user on customer website or profile information).

Sourcefabric logs the originating IP address of an end user to avoid fraudulent use (e.g. denial of service attack).

4\. Visiting our Website

In addition to Sec 2.1 and Sec 2.2 above, the following processing of data takes place.

**4.1. Web analytics and debugging**

Sourcefabric uses the following services to optimize and debug its websites.

4.1.1. Google AnalyticsSourcefabric uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. („Google“). Google Analytics uses so-called “Cookies”. “Cookies” are text files that are stored on your computer and permit an analysis of your use of the website. The information about your website use generated by the “Cookie” (including your truncated IP address) is transmitted to a server controlled by Google in the USA and is stored there. Google uses this information to analyse your use of the website, to generate reports about website activities for website operators and to provide further services related to website and internet use. Google may also share such information with third parties to the extent it is legally required to do so and/or to the extent third parties process data on behalf of Google. You may deactivate Google Analytics with the help of a browser add-on if you do not want this website analysis. This add-on can be downloaded at: ['http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

4.1.2. Facebook pixel

The Facebook pixel collects five types of data: HTTP headers that include IP addresses, information about the web browser, page location, document, referrer and person using the website. Pixel-specific data - This includes the pixel ID and Facebook cookie. Button click data - This includes any buttons clicked by site visitors, the labels of those buttons and any pages visited as a result of the button clicks. Website field names such as "email", "address" and "quantity" when a person purchases a product or service. The pixel does not capture field values unless an advertiser includes them as part of advanced matching or optional values.

You may also deactivate Facebook pixel. This add-on can be downloaded at: [www.ghostery.com/](http://www.ghostery.com/).

4.1.3. Leadforensics

This site uses Leadforensics, a reverse IP lookup service provided by www.leadforensics.com. The service analyses your approximate physical location by region based on your internet service provider to allow us to localize our website for different countries. Leadforensics uses “Cookies” to cache your resolved location. You may also deactivate Leadofrensics with the help of a browser add-on if you do not want this reverse IP lookup service. This add-on can be downloaded at: [www.ghostery.com/](http://www.ghostery.com/).

You can prevent the storage of “Cookies” by means of the appropriate settings in your browser.

4.1.4. Segment.io

Sourcefabric uses the data analysis and event forwarding service provided by Segment.io, Inc., 101 15th St, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA to understand your use of our services. Segment.io analyses the use of our website and / or services to improve our service. Segment.io forwards analysis data to the service providers mentioned in this privacy policy. For more information on Segment.io's privacy policy, please visit <https://segment.io/privacy>. The services of Segment.io are subject to the terms of use of Segment.io, which can be found at <https://segment.io/terms>.

You may deactivate Segment.io with the help of a browser add-on if you do not want this website analysis. This add-on can be downloaded at: [www.ghostery.com/](http://www.ghostery.com/).

4.1.5. Google Tag Manager

Sourcefabric uses Google Tag Manager, an event forwarding service provided by Google. Google Tag Manager uses ”Cookies”.to analyse your use of the website. Google Tag Manager allows the integration of service providers and forwards analysis data to these providers (as outlined in this privacy policy). For more information on Google Tag Manager's terms of service and privacy policy, please visit [www.google.com/analytics/tag-manager/use-policy/](http://www.google.com/analytics/tag-manager/use-policy/).

You may deactivate Google Tag Manager with the help of a browser add-on if you do not want this website analysis. This add-on can be downloaded at: [www.ghostery.com/](http://www.ghostery.com/).

**4\. 2. Identity services**

Sourcefabric allows website visitors to create a user account and log in with the following third-party identity providers.

4.2.1. GitHub

Sourcefabric allows sign-up and log-in through GitHub, a Git repository hosting service of GitHub Inc., 88 Colin P Kelly Jr St, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. For more information, see GitHub’s Privacy Statement at <https://help.github.com/articles/github-privacy-statement/>.

4.2.2. Google Authentication

Sourcefabric allows sign-up and log-in through a Google account, provided by Google. For more information, see Google’s Privacy Statement at [www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

**4\. 3. Social sharing**

Sourcefabric allows website visitors to share content such as blog posts through social media.

4.3.1. Twitter

Sourcefabric uses the Twitter plugin on its website. Twitter is a microblogging service of Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103(“Twitter”). Twitter plugins on our websites are usually marked with Twitter’s logo which is a little bird. When you enter a page on our website that contains a Twitter plugin your browser will directly connect to Twitter’s servers where the plugin is loaded from. Twitter may be able to track your visiting on our website. If you are actively using a Twitter plugin, Twitter may even process more data and publish content that you are entering into the dialogue box (“twittering”). By following a link to Twitter set on our website, data is transferred to Twitter. You need to create an account for more advanced functions of Twitter. We would like to point out that we do not have any knowledge of the content of the transmitted data as well as its use by Twitter beyond the data published there expressly, that means publicly available data.

For more information on your rights and on how Twitter is recording and processing data please see Twitter’s Privacy Policy which is available at <https://twitter.com/privacy>.

**4.4. Advertising and retargeting**

Sourcefabric uses advertising services to create awareness of its website. The advertising services track actions such as signups and use retargeting functionality to provide personalized advertisements.

4.4.1. Google Adwords

Sourcefabric uses so-called "retargeting" from Google ("Remarketing with Google Ad-Words"). A Javascript code is integrated into the website of Sourcefabric ("retargeting tag"), with the help of which Google can collect pseudonym data for advertising purposes. When a sourcefabric web page containing a "retargeting tag" is accessed, Google places a cookie on the user's device and associates it with particular retargeting groups in order to provide personalized advertising on other websites. For more detailed information on how this information is collected, please visit Google's Privacy Policy regarding Google Remarketing, which is available at: [www.google.com/privacy/ads](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads). You may object to the collection of pseudonyms for retargeting purposes by specifying under one of the links below that you do not want to receive personalized advertising by Remarketings with Google Ad-Words:

  * For Google: [www.google.com/ads/preferences/?hl=en](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/?hl=en)
  * For the US: [www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/)
  * For Europe: [www.youronlinechoices.eu/](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

4.4.2. Facebook Ads

Sourcefabric uses the retargeting function "Custom Audiences" provided by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook"). For this feature, we embed a Facebook retargeting tag on our website. This retargeting tag allows sourcefabric to display personalized and interest-related ads to our website’s visitors when they visit Facebook.

With the help of this tag, data such as which website you visited is transferred to Facebook. For this purpose, a direct connection to the Facebook servers is established, when you visit our website. Facebook assigns this information to your personal Facebook account.

For more information on your rights and how Facebook collects and uses your data please see the Facebook privacy policy at [www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/](http://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/) and www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation. If you do not want Facebook to map the collected information directly to your Facebook user account, you can disable the Retargeting Custom Audiences feature at [www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/](http://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/). In order to do so, you must be logged in to Facebook.

4.4.3. Twitter Ads

Sourcefabric uses the retargeting function "Tailored Audiences” provided by Twitter. For this feature, we embed a Twitter retargeting tag on our website. This retargeting tag allows sourcefabric to display personalized and interest-related ads to our website’s visitors when they visit Twitter.

With the help of this tag, data such as which website you visited is transferred to Twitter. For this purpose, a direct connection to the Twitter servers is established, when you visit our website. Twitter assigns this information to your personal Twitter account.

For more information on your rights and how Twitter collects and uses your data please see the Twitter privacy policy at <https://twitter.com/privacy>. If you do not wish Twitter to map the collected information directly to your Twitter account, you can disable the "Custom Audiences" retargeting feature at <https://twitter.com/login?redirect_after_login=%2Fsettings%2Fsecurity>. In order to do so, you must be logged in to Twitter.

**4.5. Support**

Sourcefabric allows website visitors to ask questions through live chat and a support system

4.5.1. LiveChat

Sourcefabric uses the live messaging service provided by LiveChat, Inc. One International Place, Suite 1400, Boston, MA 02110-2619, United States of America. to provide you live chat on the website. Intercom uses “Cookies” to allow you to chat with our agents across multiple pages when using our website. For this purpose, the information generated by the “Cookie” is transferred to an Intercom server in the USA and stored there.

For more information on your rights and on how LiveChat is processing data please see LiveChat Privacy Policy which is available at [www.livechatinc.com/privacy-policy/](http://www.livechatinc.com/privacy-policy/) .

You may deactivate Intercom with the help of a browser add-on if you do not want this live chat functionality. This add-on can be downloaded at: [www.ghostery.com/](http://www.ghostery.com/).

4.5.2. Zendesk

Sourcefabric uses the support service provided by Zendesk Inc. (“Zendesk”), Market St, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA to provide you support functionality on the website. Zendesk uses “Cookies” to allow you to log into a support portal to provide an overview of all your inquiries. For this purpose, the information generated by the “Cookie” is transferred to a Zendesk server in the USA and stored there.

For more information on your rights and on how Zendesk is processing data please see Zendesk’s Privacy Policy which is available at [www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#privacy-policy](http://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#privacy-policy).

You may deactivate Zendesk with the help of a browser add-on if you do not want this support functionality. This add-on can be downloaded at: [www.ghostery.com/](http://www.ghostery.com/).

### 5\. Changes to privacy policy

Sourcefabric reserves the right to modify this privacy policy. The current version of the privacy policy is always accessible at https://www.sourcefabric.org/en/home/policies/

This policy was updated May 24, 2018
